outdoorproject.com 2019-08-13

# Privacy Policy | Outdoor Project

Outdoor Project Privacy Policy

Outdoor Project, Inc. (“Outdoor Project,” “our,” “us,” or “we”) provides the outdoorproject.com website and various related services (together, the “Site”). This Privacy Policy describes how Outdoor Project collects, uses and discloses the personal information we receive through your use of the Site. When you use the Site, you give your permission to allow us to collect, transfer, manipulate, store, disclose or otherwise use your email address or other personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. You agree to this Privacy Policy by accessing or using the Site. This Privacy Policy applies to Outdoor Project only. It does not apply to entities and third parties that Outdoor Project does not own or control.

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at support_at_outdoorproject.com.

Information We Receive  
When you use the Site or register to create an account with the Site and become a Member, you provide us with, or grant us access to, or permission to obtain, personal information that may be used to identify or contact you (“Personal Information”), such as your email address, personal name, phone number, pictures of you, mailing address and your billing information (for example, credit card number and billing address). In addition, we may receive other information that you provide to us, such as information that we receive through your use of Outdoor Project, such as your profile details, comments, postings or other content you provide. You realize that your use of Outdoor Project may result in the sharing of information that is instantly known to anyone.

Content that you share when you use Outdoor Project may have metadata (data that may not be obvious to you but consists of information about your content). If you do not want us to store metadata, please remove the metadata before uploading the content.

When you register for Outdoor Project through your Facebook account, you provide us with Personal Information from your use of the Facebook account, such as your email address, first and last name, birthday, location and profile picture. In addition to this information, any information set to “Everyone” in your Facebook privacy settings is publicly available information and is received by Outdoor Project when you register using your Facebook account. This information may include, but may not be limited to, your gender, hometown, friends, family, relationships, networks, activities, interests, places, political views and religious views. Please visit Facebook for more about its Login/Connect feature and privacy terms at <http://www.facebook.com/help/?page=730>. Outdoor Project, however, is not responsible for any failure by Facebook to keep your personal information private.

Cookies and Web Beacons. Outdoor Project may use “cookies” (a cookie is a string of information that is sent by a web site and stored on your hard drive or temporarily in your computer or other device’s memory) to make the Site easier to use, to allow you to take advantage of Outdoor Project's special features and to make Outdoor Project's advertising relevant. Cookies can be removed or blocked using your browser’s settings, but this may impact your use of Outdoor Project. You may also receive cookies and web beacons from us or our advertisers. Web beacons are invisible images used to recognize users and assess traffic patterns; they do not use your name, email address or any other personal identifiable information. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Outdoor Project only and does not cover the use of cookies or web beacons by any third-parties.

User Device, Browsers and Log Data. Outdoor Project may receive information about the particular device you are using for Outdoor Project, such as type of computer, mobile phone, computer tablet or other device. We may also receive information about your browser type, location, and Internet Protocol address, pages you visit or have visited, search terms, referring domain and interactions with advertisements.

Links. Outdoor Project has links to other websites. Please be aware that Outdoor Project is not responsible for the privacy practices of any other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personal information.

How We Use Information We Receive

Outdoor Project may use information we receive: (i) for the purposes for which you specifically provided the information, (ii) to contact you or to provide customer service about our products and services, (iii) to enhance existing features or develop new features, products and services, (iv) to provide advertisers and other third parties with aggregate (non-personally identifiable) information about our user base and usage patterns, and (v) to allow us to target advertising to our users using specifications provided to us by third-party advertisers.

Outdoor Project Members. When you register an account with us as a Member, we will display some of your personal information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Site. For example, users of Outdoor Project will see your profile picture, name, your Member status and your completed adventures. Outdoor Project users will also see information related to your adventures on the Site, including, but not limited to, photos you upload, adventures you contribute (Contributors only) or complete, and reviews of adventures you post via the Site. Providing your personal information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with others.

By providing Outdoor Project your email address, you agree to our using your email address to send any notices required by law or other notices relating to Outdoor Project’s policies in lieu of postal mail. In addition, we may use your email address to send you notices about important changes to Outdoor Project, new services or special offers. You may opt out of receiving these types of emails by unsubscribing or emailing us at support_at_outdoorproject.com.

We will not share your personal information outside of Outdoor Project unless you have consented to having your personal information shared with a company that is not affiliated with us. If we do share your personal information with another company not affiliated with us, that information is subject to that company’s privacy policies. However, we may disclose and use personally identifiable information in special circumstances where it is necessary to enforce our Terms of Use or when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires us to do so.

We also use your personal information to contact you with Outdoor Project newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or via the “My Account” section of the Site. (See “Changing or Deleting Information” below.)

From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys, contests or sweepstakes (together, “Promotions”) through the Site. If you decide to participate, we will request some personal information from you. Participation in these Promotions is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use this information to administer your participation in each Promotion.

Social Sharing. The Site gives you the option to share information with certain social networking services (including but not limited to Twitter and Facebook). When you choose to share information about your activities on Outdoor Project with social networking services, those services may make that information visible to their users in accordance with applicable law, their data use policies, and your privacy settings for those social networking services. 

Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information. We may share aggregated information that includes your Personal Information, non-identifying information and log data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.

Service Providers. We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Site, to provide the Site on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, payment processing, web analytics and improvement of the Site’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Business Transfers. In the event that Outdoor Project is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. This Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement. Outdoor Project cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Outdoor Project or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

Changing or Deleting Your Information. All Members may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their Account by contacting us or via the “My Profile” section of the Site. If you completely delete all such information, then your Account may become deactivated. If you would like us to delete your Account in our system, please contact us at support_at_outdoorproject.com with a request that we delete your Personal Information from our database. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes.

International Transfer. Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Outdoor Project transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Changes to this Policy. We may change or revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will be at <https://outdoorproject.com/privacy-policy>. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review the Privacy Policy from time to time and to familiarize yourself with any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at support_at_outdoorproject.com or:

Outdoor Project, Inc.  
412 NW Couch Street  
Suite 202  
Portland, OR 97209

This Privacy Policy was last updated: August 31, 2018  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of: April 30, 2013
